First, please introduce your true self.
那麼首先，先做個真正的自我介紹吧
My real name is Koroku Yamabe.
我真正的名字是山部呼六
Grandma.
外婆
Ken is on the radio show.
研先生去上廣播了
Really?
什麼？研先生嗎？
I am hoping that Tsugumi will respond to Ken's voice.
我想聽了研先生的聲音 繼實應該會有些反應才對
I have worked hard since I was a child.
從小就在工作
Wait a minute.
等…等等
What are you talking about?
你在說什麼呢？
I'm talking about myself before I became a monster.
接下來我要說的 是我成為怪物之前的故事
He got his old memory back.
他記起以前的回憶了
-Is that before he became Ken? -Right.
-是成為研之前的記憶嗎？ -是啊
Why was I born?
我是為了什麼而生？
Why did Dr. Fukashi raise me?
博士為何要讓我重生？
I have been thinking about that.
我一直很煩惱這件事
Sometimes I hold grudges against him
對於博士所發現的科學力量
and the power of science that he had developed.
我也曾經怨恨過博士，但是
But I finally understood why I was born.
我總算明白為什麼我會誕生了
I would like to talk about that to someone who is precious to me
關於這件事 我想告訴拼命地想在這世上
and is trying so hard to live right now.
活下來的重要人們
It's a love story from 120 years ago.
這是120年前的戀愛故事
Hundred and twenty years ago,
120年前
I had a big dream.
我曾有個偉大的夢想
There it is!
有…有了
I visited someone to make my dream come true.
為了實現這夢想，我去拜訪了某個人
Hello.
不好意思
Is anyone here?
有人嗎？有人在家嗎？
Hello?
-不好意思 -來了…
Who is it?
有什麼事嗎？
I am Koroku Yamabe. I came from Tokyo.
我是從東京來的，我叫山部呼六
From Tokyo?
東京啊？
Yes. I am a doctor.
對，我是醫生
My name is Shimizu,
研究所把事務託付給我
I see.
您是事務長啊？
-How can I help you? -Oh, yes.
-有什麼事嗎？ -是
I would like to see Dr. Kentaro Fukashi.
我想找深志研太郎博士
I have a recommendation letter from Mr. Ohgaki,
這是我任職醫院的
the president of the hospital that I was working for.
大垣院長寫的介紹信
I heard that President Ohgaki was a classmate of Dr. Fukashi.
我聽說大垣院長 跟深志先生是同學關係
Please tell him that I would like to see him.
麻煩了
-Okay. Please wait here. -Sure.
-請稍候一下 -是
Dr. Fukashi is in this laboratory.
深志博士就在這間研究室裡
He is busy and has no time to see a volunteer like you.
總不能每次都為了像你這樣的志願者
I admire his attitude.
那還真令人欣慰啊
You have no right to say such a thing.
輪不到你欣慰吧？
-You are completely correct. -What?
-您說的沒錯 -什麼？
Excuse me.
打擾了
Hello. I am Koroku Yamabe.
打擾了，我是山部呼六
I would like to see Dr. Kentaro Fukashi.
我是來找深志研太郎博士的
Are you a believer of the academic clique?
你也是學閥主義的嗎？
Yes?
什麼？
You must be an alumnus of Teidai. That's why you worked for Ohgaki.
待在大垣手下 就表示你也是帝大的人吧？
Do you want to work for me and add luster to your career?
是要來我這裡提升資歷的嗎？
I am only a high school graduate.
我只有高等小學校畢業
But I really wanted to work for you,
即使如此 我還是想在深志博士的手下學習
so I asked President Ohgaki to write a recommendation letter.
向大垣院長千拜託萬拜託 好不容易他才幫我寫了介紹信
How did you become a doctor?
你是怎麼當上醫生的？
My family is farmers in Toyama.
是，我生在富山農家
Many people, including my family and teachers, supported me
能去上高等小學校 若沒有家人和老師們
to graduate high school.
眾多的幫助，是不可能辦到的
I wanted to become a doctor to repay their kindness.
為了回報他們的恩惠 我才想成為醫生
So, I became a student of a doctor in my town.
在個人開業醫生身邊實習
I studied until I turned 20, when I went to Tokyo.
學到20歲，接著就去了東京
Thanks to the support of so many people,
在那裡也受到很多醫生們幫助
I passed the Examination for Medical Practitioners.
總算考上了醫師執照
Did you study by yourself?
看來你幾乎都是自學的啊
Yes. I appreciate all the people's kindness.
是的，沒有比自學 更能感受到他人恩惠的方式了
You studied hard to become a doctor. Why did you come to the institution?
既然已經成為醫生了 為何要來這間研究所？
Yes.
是
After I became a doctor, I realized that
我成為醫生之後最大的感慨
there were so many diseases that a doctor couldn't cure.
是世上有太多無法醫治的疾病了
My grandmother, my brothers, and sisters died of cholera when I was a child.
我在小時候，祖母跟手足都死於霍亂
Doctors can cure only a limited number of diseases.
即使當上醫生 能治好的病還是很有限
But I heard of your achievements.
那時我得知了博士您的功績
You delivered outstanding academic results in Germany, the UK, and the US
您在德國、英國、美國都有實績
and opened the Institute of Infectious Diseases in Japan.
當我知道您回到日本 設立了這間傳染病研究所時
I was so excited when I learned about it.
真的是興奮極了
I want to study bacteriology under you
我想在博士手下學習
You seem to be very good at receiving favors from many people.
你似乎…很會給人添麻煩啊
I want to be good at returning the favor.
我也希望能趕快變得擅長報恩
I will study hard.
請您多指教
Dr. Fukashi hired me as a contact point for patients.
博士之所以讓我待在身邊
-A contact point? -Yes.
-跟病患接觸？ -是
He was not good at interacting with people.
我想是因為博士很不擅長跟人接觸
He wanted me to look after the patients
所以才把應對病患的工作交給我
so that he could concentrate on his studies.
埋首於研究
Your pulse is getting stable.
看來脈搏也安定下來了
Really?
-真的嗎？ -是
-Are you all right? -Since I loved interacting with people,
我…
I was happy to take care of the patients.
所以一點也不引以為苦
Here is lunch.
用餐時間到囉
Soup again?
又是這個啊…
I decided that I wanted to help the patients more.
接著我越來越想為病患多做些什麼
Do you want to grow vegetables?
你想種蔬菜？
There is agricultural land around the institution that is not in use.
研究所周遭有很多用不到的田地
We should make use of it.
沒理由不利用那些農地
We can grow fresh vegetables and feed them every day.
只要在那裡種新鮮蔬菜 就能每天讓病患吃了
-Who will grow them? -Me.
-誰要種啊？ -我
I am good at farming.
我很擅長做粗活的
Hey!
我說你啊
People here are alumni of Teidai.
這裡都是帝大畢業的人
They hate people who meddle.
最討厭這種雞婆事了
You are an apprentice student.
你只不過是個實習生
People will look down on you if you work like a servant
幹這種粗活，會越來越被人瞧不起
and you will feel uneasy to work here.
恐怕會待不下去啊
-Mr. Shimizu! -Yes?
-清水事務長！ -什麼事？
Which do you think is important, the patients or me?
你…認為病患跟我，哪個比較重要？
I visited a landlord to rent the farmland.
我為了借田地，去拜訪了地主的家
That's where I met Saki.
在那裡，我遇到一位名叫早紀的女性
She is an ancestor of the lady whom I'm in love with now.
她就是我現在愛上的重要女性的祖先
Is that Tsugumi?
津輕？
Is that her grandmother?
祖先…是外婆嗎？
That's too young.
外婆也太年輕了吧
Is that her grand-grandmother?
還是外婆的外婆？
I guess so. It was 120 years ago.
120年前大概是吧
I saw her picture. She looked so much like Tsugumi.
我看過照片了，長得一模一樣
Show me the picture.
給我看照片
I don't have it.
我沒有啊
-Why? -Do you really not have it?
-為何你沒有啊？ -沒有嗎？
No way.
不，就說沒有了啊
Saki was the daughter of the landlord.
早紀小姐是地主先生的女兒
Oh my gosh.
不會吧？
Saki and Ken were in love?
早紀小姐跟研先生 原來有這麼深的交情啊？
Are you following his story?
外婆你跟得上這故事嗎？
Yes, of course.
當然啊
Excuse me.
不好意思
Yes.
來了
Hello.
午安
Is this the landlord's house?
那個…這裡
May I ask who you are?
請問您是哪位？
I am an apprentice student of the Institute of Infectious Diseases
我是在傳染病研究所實習的
and I am a doctor. My name is Koroku Yamabe.
醫生，山部呼六
And you are?
您是？
I am Saki. I'm his daughter.
我是地主的女兒早紀
I see.
原來是大小姐啊
I would like to see your father.
能請您讓我跟令尊見一面嗎？
May I ask you why?
您有什麼事嗎？
I would like to rent agricultural land around the institution
其實研究所附近 還有很多沒使用的農地
that is not in use now.
我想借用那裡
Agricultural land?
借用農地？
Yes. I want to grow vegetables
對，我想在那裡耕種
so that I can feed fresh vegetables to my patients.
讓病患們吃新鮮蔬菜
But you said that you are a doctor.
您不是醫生嗎？
Yes, but I am good at farm work.
我雖是醫生，但也能做農務的
I don't think it will work.
那是不可能的
Huh?
什麼？
My father was against the Institute of Infectious Diseases.
家父很反對傳染病研究所
Against?
反對？
He was the leader of the opposition movement
您不知道村人們曾聚集起來
before it was constructed.
反對建造傳染病研究所嗎？
I see.
是這樣啊
My father doesn't allow anyone to use the land around there.
周邊土地會空著 也是因為家父不讓大家使用
People are scared of the institute and won't go close.
大家很害怕研究所，所以都不敢接近
They are worried about the land pollution.
也怕會影響土地
Please don't worry about it.
不用擔心這個
Diseases won't infect land or vegetables.
疾病是不會影響土壤跟蔬菜的
I just want to grow vegetables and feed patients.
我會種菜，讓病患吃
Will that be okay with your father?
這樣的話，令尊也能了解的吧
I don't think so.
不可能的
He is still against the institution.
家父至今仍抱持反對意見
If he lends you the land,
要是認同這種要求
people will think that he accepts it.
就等於認同研究所的存在
But there are patients who try to fight against disease.
即使如此還是有病患啊
They need fresh vegetables to live.
活下去需要新鮮蔬菜
I'm sorry.
不好意思…
I don't mean to offend you.
我一點也沒有責備你的意思
I also think that my father is wrong.
我也覺得家父這麼做是不對的
What?
什麼？
As you can see, he gets overly influenced by Western culture.
雖然像這樣 比任何人都快走入西洋式的生活
He isn't consistent with himself to go against medical advancements.
卻不認同醫學進步，這很矛盾
Don't you think so?
你不覺得嗎？
All right. Let me ask him.
我明白了，我也一起拜託看看
Excuse me.
等等…
But please be careful.
但是請你小心
My father fired at the institution using his hunting rifle before.
家父也曾經拿獵槍對研究所開槍過
Let's go.
-什麼？ -好了，進去吧
Excuse me…
那個，等等…
You will be fine. I am with you.
有我在，沒問題的
Where are you going?
那個…請問要去哪裡？
My father is at my uncle's home.
家父在叔叔的家
Okay.
是
Thank you.
不好意思
A bicycle.
腳踏車…
Yes.
是
I want to ride it.
我一直想坐一次
May I?
可以嗎？
Sure.
好的，請
Excuse me.
失禮了
Please wait.
請等一下
Put your foot on the pedal.
這是踏板，請把腳放上去
Okay.
是
Excuse me.
-失禮了 -是
Slowly step on the pedal.
把腳放到踏板上，慢慢地踩動看看
-Okay.
-來了
You are good.
您很厲害呢
What are you doing?
您在做什麼？
You can let go.
請把手放開
Can I?
可以放開嗎？
I want to ride it by myself.
這樣就不算我自己在騎了啊
Okay.
是
You are so good.
騎得很好
Oh, wait.
大小姐…
Are you all right?
沒事吧？
-I'm sorry. -It's no problem.
-對不起… -不會
Did you get hurt?
您…沒受傷吧？
Now I know that…
回想起來，那時我…
I fell in love with her at that moment.
應該就已經墜入情網了
Hi, Koroku!
呼六先生
Hi, Saki. What's wrong?
早紀小姐，怎麼了？
It's a lot of work for one person. Let me help you.
你一個人很辛苦吧？我也來幫忙
I can't let you do that.
不能讓你做這種事啊
I can do it.
我可以的
No… wait.
不，那個…
Please let me do it.
請讓我做吧
It's dangerous.
不，這很危險的
I wanted to do it since I was a child.
我從小就想試試看
You told me that before.
早紀小姐，你又來了
Please teach me.
請教教我吧
Okay.
我明白了
Here.
來
Be careful.
早紀小姐，小心
Try slowly.
慢慢地…
Here you go.
來
The sun will set by the time you finish it.
早紀小姐，這樣下去天都要黑囉
Hey, wait!
等等…
Here you go.
很好…
We're getting there.
好…
Saki! Saki!
早紀…
What are you doing?
你在做什麼啊？
Hi.
姊姊
Stop it.
別做那種事啊
Dad will kill you if he knows what you are doing.
要是被父親看到了，會被殺的
Why don't you join us?
姊姊要不要也一起試試看？
It's fun.
很好玩的唷
-Let's go. -Hey, what are you doing?
-我們走吧 -等等
Saki came to help me every day.
那之後早紀小姐也每天跑來幫我
Are you all right, Saki?
早紀小姐…沒事吧？
Look at your face.
你的臉都髒了
-Here you go. -Okay!
-來 -好
Grow well.
好好地長大吧
Here you go.
來
Thanks to you, I finished planting the seeds
多虧有早紀小姐 播種工作很快就完成了
Thank you.
謝謝
I can't wait to harvest them.
我也很期待收割
Right.
是
Are you all right?
那個…你沒問題吧？
Yes. See?
是…沒問題的，你瞧
Good.
不，這…
I wish I could take you home,
我想送你回家
but I have to go back. My patients are waiting for me.
但病患還在等，我必須先回研究所了
-I envy you. -Huh?
-我很羨慕你 -什麼？
I can't live like you.
因為我沒辦法選擇那樣的人生
Why?
為什麼？
All I know is I will marry someone
總有一天我必須結婚
someday that my parents will choose.
跟我父母決定的對象
I'm the same.
我也是一樣的
There's someone I want to marry, but I can't, no matter what.
無論我多渴望 也無法跟我想要的人結婚
Yes.
是的
Is there anything that I can do…
有什麼我能幫上忙的事嗎？
with you?
跟你一起
You mean to marry?
是…是說結婚嗎？
I mean to help the institution.
我是說研究所的事
But there is nothing…
但是，關於這個…
I hope that the patients will get well
那就跟我一起祈願
and there will be no infectious diseases.
希望病患的病都能治好
Will you hope for that with me?
祈禱傳染病能從世上消失，可以嗎？
Yes.
好的
I will hope for that with you.
我會跟你一起祈禱的
Good.
是
Saki built a statue of Jizou near the Institution.
早紀小姐這麼說
-You talked about him before. -Yes.
-就是這位啊？ -對
This is Saki. She is the daughter of the landlord.
這位是地主的千金，早紀小姐
She is the one who built a statue of Jizou for the patients.
早紀小姐為了病患 蓋了一個小地藏菩薩
Praying to God, huh?
求神拜佛啊…
Yes?
-什麼？ -呼六
Take care of the patients.
病患就拜託你了
Dr. Fukashi had another laboratory at that time.
那時博士還有另一間研究所
It's somewhere deep in the forest. No one knows about it.
隱藏在誰也不知道的森林深處
I found it.
找到了…
Later, I found out that he was studying the bacteria
我也是後來才知道的，博士在那裡
that was not the cause of a disease.
從事著跟細菌不同的菌類研究
He collected bacteria from all over the world
博士收集了全世界的菌類
and brought them to Japan.
帶回日本
He was trying to create new bacteria in that small laboratory.
在那間研究小屋試圖培育出新的菌種
He was absorbed in a study of eternal life.
博士在那裡研究著不老不死的方法
-Eternal life? -Yes.
-不老不死？ -對
Do you mean a life that is immortal and forever young?
也就是能保持年輕的樣子
Yes.
是的
He believed that some bacteria could keep human cells alive forever.
他相信有種菌類 能讓人類細胞永續存活
He never could have imagined
但是他…
that he would raise a monster in the end.
肯定沒想過那會孕育出怪物
Hello.
午安
Now, I can feed fresh vegetables to the patients.
這樣就能讓病患吃新鮮的蔬菜了
-Thank you, Saki. -My pleasure.
-都是託早紀小姐的福 -我也很高興
I'm happy to help you.
今後希望也能繼續讓我幫忙
Huh?
怪了
What's this mushroom?
這是什麼菌菇呢？
Mushroom?
菌菇？
Dr. Fukashi thinks that mushrooms have infinite possibilities.
博士認為菌菇擁有無限的力量
Infinite possibilities?
無限的力量？
The possibilities to cure diseases.
就是治療疾病的力量
That's why he goes to the forest very often.
所以他才頻繁地跑到森林去
All I think about when I see mushrooms
我就算看到菌菇
is it looks delicious or it may be poisonous.
也只會想到看起來很好吃 或有沒有毒
Dr. Fukashi is a great person.
博士真的很了不起
Compared to him, I am nothing.
我根本跟不上他的腳步
You may not go ahead of others,
你就算不走在別人前面
but you are a doctor who backs up and walks with people.
也是走在人們後面支持著大家的醫生
Oh…
不…
I…
我…
I like you a lot.
最喜歡這樣的你了
You work hard for the patients, even if you're covered in mud.
就算全身泥濘 還是為了病患努力的你
I wish I could support you.
若我今後能繼續支持…
I'm sorry.
對不起
Saki and I were in love.
我跟早紀小姐深深地愛上了對方
Hello.
辛苦了
Mr. Shimizu.
清水事務長
Saki helped the institution a lot.
早紀小姐也為了研究所盡了很多力量
Mr. Shimizu came to appreciate her.
不知不覺中，事務長也很感謝她
-Are you ready? -Yes.
-要拍囉 -是
Now!
好
Don't move.
別動唷
-Okay. Thank you. -Thank you.
-好了，謝謝 -謝謝
-Here you go.
-來，請喝
Doctor, this is delicious.
-是 -醫生，這真的很美味呢
That's good.
真是太好了
Excuse me.
打擾了
Dr. Fukashi, I brought some vegetable stew for you.
深志博士
We cooked it using fresh vegetables.
是用剛採收的蔬菜做的
Please eat it before it gets cold.
請趁熱喝吧
I heard that you like mushrooms, so I added some mushrooms.
聽說博士喜歡菌菇 所以裡面也放了菇
Tell Koroku that no one is allowed to enter here.
告訴呼六別讓任何人來這裡
Why are you keeping others at a distance?
為何博士要如此閃避人群呢？
I'm sorry.
很抱歉
I am just curious.
我只是想知道而已
Sorry for disturbing you.
抱歉打擾您了
Excuse me.
我失陪了
Emotion bothers me.
情感只會造成困擾
Emotion bothers you?
情感會造成困擾？
Wherever I go,
無論到什麼國家
there are always people who criticize me emotionally
當我展現出研究成果
when I get good results.
總是會遇上許多情緒化地責怪我的人
Many people admire you.
很多人都非常尊敬博士您啊
When you get close to others,
只要變得親近
what they will ask in return is beyond our abilities.
就會要求彼此能力之外的回報
That's when you start being miserable.
這就是不幸的開始
It's the same for men and women.
男女關係也是一樣的
The same?
一樣？
When you start talking with emotion, it disrupts your studies eventually.
話語中帶有情感時，總是會擾亂研究
To avoid that, I must get rid of all human relationships.
為了排除這些 只能徹底排除人際關係
Do you despise me?
你對我感到輕蔑嗎？
No.
不
I respect you more.
我還是很尊敬您
You are a great person.
博士真的很厲害
Invisible great power must drive you to work.
支持著博士您的 肯定是看不到的偉大力量吧
I think that power gives you freedom.
一定是這股力量帶來了自由
I think you are wonderful just the way you are.
我認為博士這樣沒什麼不好
Excuse me.
我現在就離開
After I got my old memory back…
我…想起了當時的記憶
I went to my house in the forest, where I lived for 120 years…
然後，我跑回 住了120年的森林之家
because I remembered that he wrote something
因為我想起博士在死前
just before his death.
曾寫了些什麼
It was about his studies and nothing more.
但是…那只是單純的研究紀錄
I looked everywhere.
我試圖找出其他東西
And I found something.
然後…我找到了
If Koroku regains his memory someday,
總有一天 要是恢復記憶的呼六來到這裡
there's something I have to confess.
我將向他坦承
I started liking Saki, who was your girlfriend.
我…對於你的戀人，早紀
The world is full of envy and ambition,
在充滿慾望跟野心的世界裡
but I thought I got a fair evaluation for the first time.
我感覺自己似乎第一次 受到別人的正面評價
How about this one?
這也是
Doctor, I brought some stew for you.
博士，我送湯來了
I started to have a desire to get her to admire me.
我開始想獨佔早紀小姐對我的好評
Would you like to eat with me?
要不要一起吃飯？
Yes?
什麼？
And Koroku?
把呼六也找來吧
Sure. My pleasure.
是，我很樂意
It's delicious.
真美味呢
Are you going to marry her?
兩位會結婚嗎？
Are you planning on marrying someone?
博士不會結婚嗎？
You like mushrooms more than ladies, don't you?
博士比起女性，更喜歡菌菇吧？
Some mushrooms…
菌菇有分成藉由分解木頭 使其腐爛
Others share nourishment with the roots of trees and live with them.
也有和木根分享營養 一起生存的菌菇
Both are necessary to nature.
這都是自然所不可或缺的
I think the same can be said about humans.
關於這個…人不也一樣嗎？
Marriage is not a natural thing.
結婚並非自然的事
Don't you love someone?
那麼…博士會戀愛嗎？
I'm sure you have fallen in love before.
博士肯定也有談過戀愛吧？
I can't say never.
不能說沒有
What was she like?
對方是怎樣的人呢？
I'm sure she was a wonderful lady.
一定是很棒的人吧
I wish I could meet her.
真想見一面呢
My father is rushing to arrange my marriage.
父親想讓我盡快結婚
Doctor.
博士
Do you think I should get married?
我是否應該結婚呢？
Or should I keep loving someone?
還是應該戀愛呢？
I'm sorry to say, but…
很遺憾
not many people can become happy by loving someone in this country.
在這國家，靠戀愛獲得幸福的人很少
I'm sure it's not easy.
所以需要做好覺悟
But I think you two can make it.
你們一定沒問題的
Thank you, Doctor.
都是託先生的福，真的
When you got a new kind of infectious disease,
所以，當你染上新的傳染病時
I couldn't help but think that I could take Saki from you.
我在那瞬間
Doctor? Someone help!
醫生？來人啊…
I have the most unrespectable human emotion in my mind.
我萌生了人類最卑鄙的情感
Dr. Fukashi.
博士…
Saki.
早紀小姐
You shouldn't come here.
你不能來這裡啊
Don't worry.
沒問題的
Dr. Fukashi told me that he would cure your disease
博士說他會治好你的
by making a new medicine.
會有新的藥
I will always be with you.
我會永遠跟你在一起
I promise you.
我答應你
Dr. Fukashi tried so hard to cure my disease.
博士拼命地想治好我
However…
但是…
he couldn't get a new serum ready in time.
新的血清來不及研發出來
Koroku?
呼六先生？
Koroku.
呼六先生…
I knew nothing about humans.
我不懂人類
I didn't understand Saki at all.
也不懂早紀小姐的心
I was wrong to leave her with him as long as she wanted.
是我不該讓早紀小姐一直待在你身邊
Saki! Saki!
早紀小姐…
She took poison and tried to kill herself to be with him.
早紀小姐偷了藥劑 打算跟著你一起死
She might have escaped death.
所幸她撿回了一命
But no one could guarantee that she could live without him.
但我沒辦法保證她能繼續活下去
I wanted to save her from despair.
希望能將她從絕望中拯救出來的我
I couldn't have thought of anything but to take the last resort…
只能選擇最後的手段
which was to raise you from death to see her again.
我想讓她再見你一面
I decided to inject the bacteria into your dead body.
然後，我把那個菌類
GERMAN: ETERNAL LIFE
（永恆的生命）
Eternal life.
永恆的生命
I found it.
找到了…
I wasn't jealous of you at that time.
那時的我 失去了所有對你的嫉妒之心
It wasn't even for Saki.
曾幾何時，不再是為了早紀小姐
I just wanted to save you.
只是一心想使你復活
I was overjoyed at your recovery from death.
所以當你重生時，我真的非常高興
However…
然而
you knew what had happened.
那之後的事你也知道
I sent you back to Saki after I raised you from death.
我打算讓重生的你和早紀小姐見面
I didn't expect your change.
只有那個異變出於我的計算之外
It was my fault.
然後…
I shouldn't have let you do that.
我讓你做出了那樣的事
You became a horrible monster because of me.
我讓你變成了可怕的怪物
Koroku.
呼六啊
I am so sorry.
真的很抱歉
I see.
原來如此
There was something that I finally realized.
但是，我總算明白了
Yes?
明白什麼？
I was born because Dr. Fukashi was in love.
我…是從博士的愛情而生的
I was raised from his feelings for her.
是從博士對人的愛情而誕生的
It was not hatred, anger, ambition, or desire of humans
我不是來自於人類的憎恨 憤怒、野心或慾望
but love of humans that gave life to me.
我是從人類的愛情而誕生的
That's why I could love humans.
所以…我想我應該也能愛上人類
That's why I fell in love with you.
然後…
My body can discharge the bacteria that kills humans,
我的體內也有會殺死人類的菌
but I don't want to hurt anyone.
但是，我不想傷害任何人
I don't want to kill anyone.
我不想殺死任何人
I want to help someone if I can.
如果可以的話，我想幫忙
I want to help people, just like Dr. Fukashi did.
我希望能幫助人們 我想連同博士的份一起
This is my honest feeling.
現在我是這麼想的
This is my truth.
這就是…關於我的真相
What are you doing, Amakusa?
天草先生，你在做什麼？
You should talk back to him.
快反駁啊
Tell him that it must all be fake.
快說這都是捏造的，快說啊
Say that you don't believe what he just said.
快說天草先生你不相信啊
You should say that for the sake of the show and yourself.
這是為了節目，也是為了你自己啊
Amakusa!
天草先生！
Deny him!
快否定啊！
Hey.
等等
Amakusa, keep going.
天草，繼續下去吧
This is my show.
這是我的節目
Thank you very much for telling us the truth.
謝謝你…說出真相
You didn't know anything.
你自己也不知道這些事
You've been bearing the anxiety and loneliness for 120 years
120年來一直忍受著不安跟孤獨吧
as a monster who can't die.
以一個無法死去的怪物的身分
Yes.
是
Do you still want to live with humans…
現在，你想跟人類一起生活嗎？
even if you have a dangerous bacteria?
就算體內有如此可怕的菌
Because I am a monster who has a dangerous bacteria,
正因為我有這些菌 正因為我是個怪物
I fell in love with humans
所以我才會愛上人類
and I learned how wonderful they are, more than anyone else.
比誰都更了解人類的美好之處
By coming on the radio show,
然後，來上廣播
I had fun for the first time in 120 years.
獲得了120年份的快樂
I also had fun seeing you, Franken.
我也一樣 能遇上怪人你，真是太棒了
Amakusa.
天草先生
I am glad that I believed what you said.
相信天草先生你的話，真是太好了
I am glad that I believed in you.
能相信天草先生你，真是太好了
What are you going to do from now on?
今後你打算怎麼辦？
I hope that she will get well soon.
希望她能趕快好起來
That's all I care about.
現在我的心願就只有這樣而已
Franken.
怪人
Thank you very much.
真的很感謝你
Amakusa.
天草先生
I thank you so much.
謝謝你
All right.
那麼
I hope to see you again.
下次再見吧
When you worry about something at snack time…
點心時間的煩惱
Ask Amakusa
就去問天草吧
Thank you.
辛苦了
Tsugumi will get well soon.
津輕小姐一定會好起來的
I'm sure she understood what you said
研先生的話語
Yes.
是
I have to go.
我要走了
Mr. Tokachi.
十勝先生
I am very sorry.
很抱歉
Okay.
嗯
You worked hard.
辛苦了
See you again.
下次見
Yes.
是
Thank you very much.
謝謝各位
ETERNAL LIFE
（永恆的生命）
HOSPITAL RECEPTION OF WARD VISITORS
（醫院訪客櫃台）
Welcome back.
歡迎回來
Hi, Ken.
研先生
Seiya.
稻庭前輩
Tsugumi was listening to your radio appearance.
我有聽廣播了，津輕小姐也是
-Then she-- -No.
-那津輕小姐… -不
She is still sleeping.
她還是沒醒來
Let's go see her.
去見見她吧
Yes.
是
-Welcome back. -Hello.
-歡迎回來 -是
I think Tsugumi wants to see you.
繼實好像很想見你
Ken. Please see her.
研先生，請跟那孩子見面吧
Thank you.
謝謝
Ken.
研先生
I went to the forest…
我去了森林一趟
to look for the house you used to live in.
我去找了研先生住的地方
Why?
為什麼？
I wanted to know about the bacteria that Dr. Fukashi had discovered
我很想知道深志博士找到的
that can make human life immortal.
能給予永恆生命的菌類
I wanted to find a clue.
我希望能找到線索
And I found it.
然後真的找到了
This is the sample he had used 120 years ago.
120年前的實驗材料 就那樣留在那裡
I studied this bacteria and found something interesting.
調查這菌類 發現了一個不可思議的事實
Something interesting?
-不可思議的事？ -這個菌類
It is very similar to the red mushroom that you grow.
和研先生的紅色菌菇很相近
You always grow red mushrooms when you are with Tsugaru.
研先生跟津輕小姐在一起時 總是會生出紅色菌菇吧？
If this mushroom is your heart…
如果這些菇就是你的心
I think you can love humans.
我認為你應該可以愛上人類
The red mushroom you grow may be the evolutionary form of this.
研先生長出的菌菇似乎就是這種菌
It means that the bacteria you have will work on human DNA
所以，研先生
and regenerate human cells.
或許擁有讓人類細胞再生的力量
Only you can create this bacteria.
這種菌只有研先生能產出
Isn't it great?
這很厲害的
I found out one more thing.
我還發現了另一件事
It's not poisonous.
就是這沒有毒性
Not poisonous?
-沒有毒性嗎？ -對
It was confirmed that the red mushroom you grow
研先生的紅色菌菇
cannot harm humans.
對人是無害的
When you are in the mental situation where you grow red mushrooms,
所以研先生想產出 紅色菌菇的心理狀態時
you can touch humans.
你可以觸碰人類的
Ken, you can touch Tsugumi.
研先生，你是可以碰觸津輕小姐的
Tsugumi.
津輕小姐
NEXT TIME
（稻庭建築公司）
Is there a person called Frankenstein?
被稱為科學怪人的人在嗎？
-Let him go! -Stop this!
-快逃啊！ -研先生照想要的活下去就行
-I want to keep Tsugumi happy. Goodbye. -Where are you, Ken?
-研先生 -我想守護津輕小姐的幸福
THIS DRAMA IS A WORK OF FICTION
（本劇純屬虛構）